<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Xiaoyun Yang</title>
    <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Xiaoyun Yang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Deploy Your Node-React-Mongo App To Amazon Web Service</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-to-deploy-your-node-react-mongo-app-to-amazon-web-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-to-deploy-your-node-react-mongo-app-to-amazon-web-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I will provide a step-by-step guide for how to containerize your Mongo/Express/React/Node (MERN) app with Docker and deploy it to Amazon Web Service (AWS) Elastic Container Service (ECS). I will share my research and lessons learned deploying a MERN app, including what worked, what didn&amp;rsquo;t work, how I prepared the app for deployment and accomplished the deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Quit Your Job To Be An Entrepreneur. Bootstrap.</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/dont-quit-your-job-to-be-an-entrepreneur.-bootstrap./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/dont-quit-your-job-to-be-an-entrepreneur.-bootstrap./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People have different reasons to want to quit their 9-5 to pursue entrepreneurship full time. I was drawn to the opportunity to take something from idea to product and being able to “be my own boss”. We all want the lifestyle of a successful entrepreneur but you don’t need to have your own VC funded startup to build a great product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Employee Loyalty Important?</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/is-employee-loyalty-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/is-employee-loyalty-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;High-value employees are a major assets for a strong company. Losing a high contributing team member could leave a void and impact the team&amp;rsquo;s morale and workflow. Investors are also concerned by high turnover rates, especially amongst the senior executives. Groupon had trouble retaining their senior executives, which contributed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zeNQE3VBRnQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an 85% drop in their value&lt;/a&gt; a year after going public. It&amp;rsquo;s clear we want to &lt;strong&gt;retain&lt;/strong&gt; high-valued employees, but is &lt;strong&gt;employee loyalty&lt;/strong&gt; the way to achieve retention?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Pay to Work At a Co-working Space</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/why-i-pay-to-work-at-a-co-working-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/why-i-pay-to-work-at-a-co-working-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you asked me to give you three facts about myself, I would tell you (1) I&amp;rsquo;m a evening and weekend entrepreneur, (2) when I start working on something I enjoy, I can&amp;rsquo;t put it down, and (3) I love coffee. This a formula for disaster because I have a full time job that I have to show up to by 9AM and I&amp;rsquo;m a normal human person who needs at least 6 hours of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Formal Education May Close Doors To Opportunities</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-formal-education-may-close-doors-to-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-formal-education-may-close-doors-to-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The average completion rate of Online Open Course (MOOC) certification programs is abysmally low. &lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2889436&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A report published in 2016 by researchers at Harvard and MIT&lt;/a&gt; based on 4 years of data indicated an average certification completion rate of just 5.5%. This does not discredit MOOCs to be a good source of quality education content for those looking for good information to improve their understanding for a particular subject; however, the depressing statistics underlines a deeper concern with the ineffectiveness of using a college curriculum to steer people&amp;rsquo;s professional development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>