<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Xiaoyun Yang</title>
    <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Xiaoyun Yang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I get 100 Hours Worth of Work Done in a 40-hour Work Week</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-i-get-100-hours-worth-of-work-done-in-a-40-hour-work-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-i-get-100-hours-worth-of-work-done-in-a-40-hour-work-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spend 3 hours at the gym every day, go on mountaineering and snowboarding trips every three months, work as a founding engineer at a Series A startup, and still have time for side projects like this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone recently asked me what’s my secret for getting all this done. How do I have time to do all these things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I’ll share my secrets on how to be hyper-productive using some theories from business books I read and insights from science (e.g. three laws of thermodynamics), with examples from my experience climbing, training at the gym, and working as a software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Surprising Life Lessons From My 30s</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/6-surprising-life-lessons-from-my-30s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/6-surprising-life-lessons-from-my-30s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks after I turned 30, the world went into a lock-down. During the COVID-19 pandemic, I&amp;rsquo;ve done a lot of growing and learning as there is a lot of time to reflect on our values and think about better ways to live a more fulfilling life. There are two categories of lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my 30s. First is how to make better tradeoffs - opportunity cost, money vs time, efficiency vs effectiveness, and quality vs quantity. Second is how to prioritize.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experience Buying a Home in NYC during the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/my-experience-buying-a-home-in-nyc-during-the-covid-19-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/my-experience-buying-a-home-in-nyc-during-the-covid-19-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I worked from home for almost 4 months since the start of the quarantine before I got a monitor for working from home. I&amp;rsquo;m a programmer. I was under the impression that we were going to be able to go back to work first in April, then May. Now the government is saying August, but I no longer trust anything the government or the media says about the reopening timeline. I’m going to assume the worst that we are going to work from home until the vaccine becomes widely available. A realistic timeline for when that will be is late 2021, early 2022. I’m making preparations for a long term social distancing, work from home situation. Buying the monitor is the first step. I’m also getting a new set of furniture and moving to a bigger apartment so I’ll have a better time staying at home for an extended period of time. COVID-19 is the catalyst for me initiating the process of purchasing a home in NY, but I&amp;rsquo;ve always planned to purchase. This is my experience buying a home in NYC in the spring / summer of 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Algorithm for Managing Stress</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/the-algorithm-for-managing-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/the-algorithm-for-managing-stress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is stress? Stress is your subconscious telling you that you have sh*t to do. Feeling stressed about your health? Go to the gym everyday. Feeling stressed about your financial situation? Get a more high paying job. If only things were that simple. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to teach you how to get rid your stress by understanding where your stress is coming from, then come up with an action plan and execute actions to address the source of your stress. This is not another &amp;ldquo;top 10 things you can do to &amp;hellip;.&amp;rdquo; article. I will be discussing specific algorithms and heuristics with roots in computer science and mathematics that can be followed for every step of your journey to eliminating the source of your stress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Public Sector To Senior Software Engineer:  How I made the Transition</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/from-public-sector-to-senior-software-engineer-how-i-made-the-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/from-public-sector-to-senior-software-engineer-how-i-made-the-transition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I joined the US Navy after graduating from college. The service commitment is 5 years. At the end of my service commitment during my terminal leave, I obtained a position with a mature startup in NYC as a Senior Software Engineer. There were a lot of bumps in the road during the last five years, especially the last 3 weeks of my transition out of the Navy. I will share the story of how I prepared for my career transition and shed some light on how job search works today.&lt;/p&gt;


 
  
  
  
  
    
  
    
      
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;figure fig-70&#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://images2.imgbox.com/26/21/MQB5dNYd_o.png&#34; title=&#34;My KeyValues filter&#34; data-fancybox=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;https://images2.imgbox.com/26/21/MQB5dNYd_o.png&#34;  alt=&#34;My KeyValues filter&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;/a&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;My KeyValues filter&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Quit Your Job To Be An Entrepreneur</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/dont-quit-your-job-to-be-an-entrepreneur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/dont-quit-your-job-to-be-an-entrepreneur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People have different reasons to want to quit their 9-5 to pursue entrepreneurship full time. I was drawn to the opportunity to take something from idea to product and being able to “be my own boss”. We all want the lifestyle of a successful entrepreneur but you don’t need to have your own VC funded startup to build a great product.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Employee Loyalty Important?</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/is-employee-loyalty-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/is-employee-loyalty-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;High-value employees are a major assets for a strong company. Losing a high contributing team member could leave a void and impact the team&amp;rsquo;s morale and workflow. Investors are also concerned by high turnover rates, especially amongst the senior executives. Groupon had trouble retaining their senior executives, which contributed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zeNQE3VBRnQ&#34;&gt;an 85% drop in their value&lt;/a&gt; a year after going public. It&amp;rsquo;s clear we want to &lt;strong&gt;retain&lt;/strong&gt; high-valued employees, but is &lt;strong&gt;employee loyalty&lt;/strong&gt; the way to achieve retention?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Pay to Work At a Co-working Space</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/why-i-pay-to-work-at-a-co-working-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/why-i-pay-to-work-at-a-co-working-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you asked me to give you three facts about myself, I would tell you (1) I&amp;rsquo;m a evening and weekend entrepreneur, (2) when I start working on something I enjoy, I can&amp;rsquo;t put it down, and (3) I love coffee. This a formula for disaster because I have a full time job that I have to show up to by 9AM and I&amp;rsquo;m a normal human person who needs at least 6 hours of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Formal Education May Close Doors To Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-formal-education-may-close-doors-to-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-formal-education-may-close-doors-to-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The average completion rate of Online Open Course (MOOC) certification programs is abysmally low. &lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2889436&#34;&gt;A report published in 2016 by researchers at Harvard and MIT&lt;/a&gt; based on 4 years of data indicated an average certification completion rate of just 5.5%. This does not discredit MOOCs to be a good source of quality education content for those looking for good information to improve their understanding for a particular subject; however, the depressing statistics underlines a deeper concern with the ineffectiveness of using a college curriculum to steer people&amp;rsquo;s professional development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
