<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xiaoyun Yang</title>
    <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Xiaoyun Yang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Complete Guide To Deploying Your Web App To Amazon Web Service</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/a-complete-guide-to-deploying-your-web-app-to-amazon-web-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/a-complete-guide-to-deploying-your-web-app-to-amazon-web-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/images/deployapp/ecs-docker.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This a comprehensive guide for how to containerize your Mongo/Express/React/Node (MERN) app with Docker and deploy it to Amazon Web Service (AWS) Elastic Container Service (ECS). I will share my research and lessons learned deploying a MERN app, including what worked, what didn&amp;rsquo;t work, how I prepared the app for deployment and accomplished the deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Developer Playbook: Rich Text Editor</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/web-developer-playbook-rich-text-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/web-developer-playbook-rich-text-editor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, I will show you add a rich text editor based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://draftjs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Draft.js&lt;/a&gt; to your web app. This post is part of the Web Developer Playbook series, created to provide examples, best practice, and suggestions for designing and building web services. I will be using libraries from the JavaScript ecosystem (e.g., Node.js, React.js) in all my examples.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/images/projects/draftjs.png&#34; alt=&#34;draftjs&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Quit Your Job To Be An Entrepreneur. Bootstrap.</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/dont-quit-your-job-to-be-an-entrepreneur.-bootstrap./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/dont-quit-your-job-to-be-an-entrepreneur.-bootstrap./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People have different reasons to want to quit their 9-5 to pursue entrepreneurship full time. I was drawn to the opportunity to take something from idea to product and being able to “be my own boss”. We all want the lifestyle of a successful entrepreneur but you don’t need to have your own VC funded startup to build a great product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Developer Playbook: Slug</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/web-developer-playbook-slug/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/web-developer-playbook-slug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/images/webdev-manual-cover.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
This post is part of the Web Developer Playbook series, which are created to provide examples, best practice, and suggestions for designing and building web services. I will be using libraries from the JavaScript ecosystem (e.g., Node.js, React.js) in all my examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Career Pivot With LooseLeaf</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/getting-started-with-career-pivot-with-looseleaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/getting-started-with-career-pivot-with-looseleaf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This documents the market research I&amp;rsquo;ve completed for my startup, &lt;a href=&#34;https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/creating-looseleaf-a-platform-to-support-the-future-of-work/&#34;&gt;LooseLeaf&lt;/a&gt;. This is a long and exhaustive market research. There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/getting-started-with-startup-seed-funding/#pre-submittal-feedback-optional&#34;&gt;TL;DR version of the value proposition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Structure with JavaScript Object: Linked List</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/data-structure-with-javascript-object-linked-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/data-structure-with-javascript-object-linked-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Linked list is like an array but more flexible. Elements in an array are stored contiguously in memory while linked lists are stored as nodes with two fields: current value and a pointer to the next thing in the list. We are going to implement linked list in JavaScript and go over some algorithms with the linked list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algos to Practice Whiteboarding for The Coding Interview</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/algos-to-practice-whiteboarding-for-the-coding-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/algos-to-practice-whiteboarding-for-the-coding-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are going to go over a set of coding and whiteboard problems that would be asked during a coding interview. I&amp;rsquo;m drawing these problems from &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LeetCode&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Cracking-Coding-Interview-Programming-Questions/dp/0984782850/ref=pd_lpo_sbs_14_t_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=2E72V7DJM4CV4DNTBTKD&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cracking the Coding Interview&lt;/a&gt;. They are a sample of the medium and hard problems that require a bit of thinking and and familiarity with some fundamental data structures in computer science.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Web App For Work</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/serverless-web-app-for-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/serverless-web-app-for-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I work at my federal job on a close intranet network, we often had to access information from different databases and filesystems through custom or share point websites which did not have the best user interface. It was a pain point for me and many of my colleagues. I decided to make a set of single page applications (SPAs) with nicer UX for querying the databases and file systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coding Interview: What to Expect</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/the-coding-interview-what-to-expect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/the-coding-interview-what-to-expect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being great at coding interviews doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily make you a great developer and being a great developer doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily make you great at interviews. However, you need to pass the interview to get the job. Most tech companies, public or startups, have started drawing from the same pool of interview material, adopted the same set of coding challenges and problems for candidates to solve. Coding interviews can be challenging and stressful, but with enough practice, research, and preparation, it can be very manageable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Wanna Be A Gopher Eh?</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/so-you-wanna-be-a-gopher-eh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/so-you-wanna-be-a-gopher-eh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Go is becoming pretty mainstream. Every job posting I&amp;rsquo;ve seen recently requires Go as a want-to-have or a need-to-have skill. Here&amp;rsquo;s a guide to help you hit the ground running with Go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Startup Seed Funding</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/getting-started-with-startup-seed-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/getting-started-with-startup-seed-funding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This documents my journey applying to the National Science Foundation (NSF) Seed Fund for my startup, &lt;a href=&#34;https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/creating-looseleaf-a-platform-to-support-the-future-of-work/&#34;&gt;LooseLeaf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With The SAM Application</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/getting-started-with-the-sam-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/getting-started-with-the-sam-application/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The System for Award Management (SAM) is the primary registrant database for entities to do business with the U.S. Government. You must register with SAM before &lt;a href=&#34;https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/getting-started-with-startup-seed-funding/&#34;&gt;applying for a seed fund from the government&lt;/a&gt; for your startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Do Object Oriented Programming The Right Way</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-to-do-object-oriented-programming-the-right-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-to-do-object-oriented-programming-the-right-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Object Oriented Programming (OOP) is a software design pattern that allows you to think about problems in terms of objects and their interactions. OOP is typically done with classes or with prototypes. Most languages that implement OOP (e.g., Java, C++, Ruby, Python) use class-based inheritance. JavaScript implements OOP via Prototypal inheritance. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to use both approaches for OOP in JavaScript, discuss the advantages and disadvantages of the two approaches of OOP and introduce an alternative for OOP for designing more modular and scalable applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles To Code By: How To Solve Problems With Code</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/principles-to-code-by-how-to-solve-problems-with-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/principles-to-code-by-how-to-solve-problems-with-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What I love most about programming is the problem solving. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe anyone is born with problem solving skills. It&amp;rsquo;s a muscle that is built and sustained by repeated exercise. Like any exercise, there&amp;rsquo;s a set of guidelines to help you be more effective at developing your problem solving muscles. I will introduce 5 of the most important software design principles that have guided my problem solving process and show you how to apply these principles to solve a real problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Career Transition Guide For Overachievers</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/a-career-transition-guide-for-overachievers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/a-career-transition-guide-for-overachievers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing strikes more anxiety and self-doubt than the dreaded job interview. The thought of participating in an activity designed for the sole purpose of evaluating your worth and the potential for rejection is enough to discourage many people from applying to jobs for which they lack all of the qualifications requested by the job posting. While qualification is important to accomplish the advertised job, it is not everything an employer looks for in a person they want to hire to be a part of the team, to grow with the company and help the company grow. The goal of this article is to provide a guide based on my personal experience for how to prepare for getting offers from jobs for which you don&amp;rsquo;t have all the qualifications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithms for Web Developers</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/algorithms-for-web-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/algorithms-for-web-developers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is one of the most popular and versatile languages today, but when Brandon Eich first created JavaScript in 1995, it was not recognized as a general purpose programming language. JavaScript only ran in the browser and was primarily used to enhance the user interfaces of website (e.g., animation, effects upon hover), thus tightly coupled with the Data Object Model (DOM). In recent years, JavaScript has gotten a lot more useful as a general purpose language as it can be run independently from the DOM and browser. Additionally, JavaScript has also has gotten very sophisticated with the introduction of ES6 and ES7. With that, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at how JavaScript can be used to solve fundamental problems in computer science. Specifically, let&amp;rsquo;s look at how to write algorithms and leverage data structures to help us solve problems using JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating LooseLeaf: A Platform To Support The Future Of Work</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/creating-looseleaf-a-platform-to-support-the-future-of-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/creating-looseleaf-a-platform-to-support-the-future-of-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://looseleafapp.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LooseLeaf&lt;/a&gt; is a passion project and a startup I&amp;rsquo;ve been building while serving a 5 year commitment in the military. I&amp;rsquo;ve been creating prototypes and iterating on the concept of LooseLeaf since 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything You Need To Know About Git</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/everything-you-need-to-know-about-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/everything-you-need-to-know-about-git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a cheatsheet of all the git commands that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever used in my career as a programmer and contributor of open source projects. I&amp;rsquo;m not a git power user (I use about three commands on a daily basis). From time to time, I still use this cheatsheet to for a quick lookup of a special command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Employee Loyalty Important?</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/is-employee-loyalty-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/is-employee-loyalty-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;High-value employees are a major assets for a strong company. Losing a high contributing team member could leave a void and impact the team&amp;rsquo;s morale and workflow. Investors are also concerned by high turnover rates, especially amongst the senior executives. Groupon had trouble retaining their senior executives, which contributed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zeNQE3VBRnQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an 85% drop in their value&lt;/a&gt; a year after going public. It&amp;rsquo;s clear we want to &lt;strong&gt;retain&lt;/strong&gt; high-valued employees, but is &lt;strong&gt;employee loyalty&lt;/strong&gt; the way to achieve retention?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Hugo To Build A Personal Brand Website</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/using-hugo-to-build-a-personal-brand-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/using-hugo-to-build-a-personal-brand-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not always clear why we need need a personal website. But here&amp;rsquo;s the truth: we are a product (a brand) with unique skills to offer to prospective employees and customers. A website is an effective medium to let the world know who we are, what we are capable of, and what our values are. Building a personal website has never been easier these days with tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Pay to Work At a Co-working Space</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/why-i-pay-to-work-at-a-co-working-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/why-i-pay-to-work-at-a-co-working-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you asked me to give you three facts about myself, I would tell you (1) I&amp;rsquo;m a evening and weekend entrepreneur, (2) when I start working on something I enjoy, I can&amp;rsquo;t put it down, and (3) I love coffee. This a formula for disaster because I have a full time job that I have to show up to by 9AM and I&amp;rsquo;m a normal human person who needs at least 6 hours of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building A React Native Travel App</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/building-a-react-native-travel-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/building-a-react-native-travel-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was planning my trip to Japan with some friends, I thought why not to use this opportunity to make a ReactNative mobile app to help you plan and execute your travel itinerary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Isomorphic Webapp</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/building-an-isomorphic-webapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/building-an-isomorphic-webapp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always lived by the &amp;ldquo;Separation of Concern&amp;rdquo; principle when it comes to software design.  Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve came to love a new design pattern for web apps called the isomorphic web app that sacrifices some of the simplicity of a SPA with a backend API for a significant boost in performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Get Productive With JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/lets-get-productive-with-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/lets-get-productive-with-javascript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is one of the most popular and versatile languages today. You can build anything in JavaScript: from full stack web apps, to cross platform mobile apps, to cross platform desktop apps. Here are some useful algorithms and syntax in JavaScript to help you be productive in JavaScript right away. No set up necessary. Just  open up your browser&amp;rsquo;s console (hit &lt;code&gt;Cmd&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;code&gt;Shift&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;code&gt;C&lt;/code&gt; if you are using Chrome and Mac) and start typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Formal Education May Close Doors To Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-formal-education-may-close-doors-to-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-formal-education-may-close-doors-to-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The average completion rate of Online Open Course (MOOC) certification programs is abysmally low. &lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2889436&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A report published in 2016 by researchers at Harvard and MIT&lt;/a&gt; based on 4 years of data indicated an average certification completion rate of just 5.5%. This does not discredit MOOCs to be a good source of quality education content for those looking for good information to improve their understanding for a particular subject; however, the depressing statistics underlines a deeper concern with the ineffectiveness of using a college curriculum to steer people&amp;rsquo;s professional development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Functional Programming Promotes Developer Productivity</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-functional-programming-promotes-developer-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-functional-programming-promotes-developer-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Functional Programming is more than just a buzzword these days. It&amp;rsquo;s super useful and makes you rethink everything you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining a Repository Of Learning For Scala</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/maintaining-a-repository-of-learning-for-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/maintaining-a-repository-of-learning-for-scala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I maintain a knowledge repo on Github called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xiaoyunyang/coursera-scala-specialization&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;coursera-scala-specialization&lt;/a&gt;. One reason I chose to learn Scala is that Scala is a good language to learn functional programming and Scala offers full the functional programming support, but it also lets you do imperative programming and object oriented programming, with seamless interoperability with Java. Functional programming is a good paradigm that lets you make programs that are concise and modular. This is important for developer productivity which I care most about at this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating NumberShapes: Math Learning Mobile Apps</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/creating-numbershapes-math-learning-mobile-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/creating-numbershapes-math-learning-mobile-apps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://number-shapes.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NumberShapes&lt;/a&gt; is a collection of mobile apps that make numbers come alive through numerical visualizations and interactions. In 2014, I worked on the software development for the first few apps, which are iOS matching games that help young learners with familiarization of addition, subtraction, multiplication and other math facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer and tech entrepreneur. I&amp;rsquo;m excited by opportunities that let me develop elegant solutions for obvious problems where there are no obvious solutions. I believe in automating wherever possible, and leveraging existing technology to quickly bootstrap solutions. My mantra is trial and error, which I apply to both building a startup as well as living a fulfilling life.
I live in Washington DC. I have a full time job and a side hustle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>