<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Webapp on Xiaoyun Yang</title>
    <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/tags/webapp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Webapp on Xiaoyun Yang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/tags/webapp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Interview Study Guide For Overachievers</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/an-interview-study-guide-for-overachievers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/an-interview-study-guide-for-overachievers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing strikes more anxiety and self-doubt than the dreaded Job Interview. The thought of participating in an activity designed for the sole purpose of evaluating your worth and the potential for rejection is enough to discourage many people from applying to jobs for which they lack all of the qualifications requested by the job posting. While qualification is important to accomplish the advertised job, it is not everything an employer looks for in a person they want to hire to be a part of the team, to grow with the company and help the company grow. The goal of this article is to provide a guide based on my personal experience for how to prepare for getting offers from jobs for which you don&amp;rsquo;t have all the qualifications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating LooseLeaf: A Platform To Support The Future Of Work</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/creating-looseleaf-a-platform-to-support-the-future-of-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/creating-looseleaf-a-platform-to-support-the-future-of-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://looseleafapp.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LooseLeaf&lt;/a&gt; is a passion project and a startup I&amp;rsquo;ve been building while serving a 5 year commitment in the military. I&amp;rsquo;ve been creating prototypes and iterating on the concept of LooseLeaf since 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Hugo To Build A Personal Brand Website</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/using-hugo-to-build-a-personal-brand-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/using-hugo-to-build-a-personal-brand-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not always clear why we need need a personal website. But here&amp;rsquo;s the truth: we are a product (a brand) with unique skills to offer to prospective employees and customers. A website is an effective medium to let the world know who we are, what we are capable of, and what our values are. Building a personal website has never been easier these days with tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Isomorphic Webapp</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/building-an-isomorphic-webapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/building-an-isomorphic-webapp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always lived by the &amp;ldquo;Separation of Concern&amp;rdquo; principle when it comes to software design.  Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve came to love a new design pattern for web apps called the isomorphic web app that sacrifices some of the simplicity of a SPA with a backend API for a significant boost in performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining a Repository Of Learning For Scala</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/maintaining-a-repository-of-learning-for-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/maintaining-a-repository-of-learning-for-scala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I maintain a knowledge repo on Github called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xiaoyunyang/coursera-scala-specialization&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;coursera-scala-specialization&lt;/a&gt;. One reason I chose to learn Scala is that Scala is a good language to learn functional programming and Scala offers full the functional programming support, but it also lets you do imperative programming and object oriented programming, with seamless interoperability with Java. Functional programming is a good paradigm that lets you make programs that are concise and modular. This is important for developer productivity which I care most about at this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>