<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career on Xiaoyun Yang</title>
    <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Career on Xiaoyun Yang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Public Sector To Senior Software Engineer:  How I made the Transition</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/from-public-sector-to-senior-software-engineer-how-i-made-the-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/from-public-sector-to-senior-software-engineer-how-i-made-the-transition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I joined the US Navy after graduating from college. The service commitment is 5 years. At the end of my service commitment during my terminal leave, I obtained a position with a mature startup in NYC as a Senior Software Engineer. There were a lot of bumps in the road during the last five years, especially the last 3 weeks of my transition out of the Navy. I will share the story of how I prepared for my career transition and shed some light on how job search works today.&lt;/p&gt;


 
  
  
  
  
    
  
    
      
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;figure fig-70&#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://images2.imgbox.com/26/21/MQB5dNYd_o.png&#34; title=&#34;My KeyValues filter&#34; data-fancybox=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;https://images2.imgbox.com/26/21/MQB5dNYd_o.png&#34;  alt=&#34;My KeyValues filter&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;/a&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;My KeyValues filter&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Career Pivot With LooseLeaf</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/getting-started-with-career-pivot-with-looseleaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/getting-started-with-career-pivot-with-looseleaf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This documents the market research I&amp;rsquo;ve completed for my startup, &lt;a href=&#34;https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/creating-looseleaf-a-platform-to-support-the-future-of-work/&#34;&gt;LooseLeaf&lt;/a&gt;. This is a long and exhaustive market research. There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/getting-started-with-startup-seed-funding/#pre-submittal-feedback-optional&#34;&gt;TL;DR version of the value proposition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algos to Practice Whiteboarding for The Coding Interview</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/algos-to-practice-whiteboarding-for-the-coding-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/algos-to-practice-whiteboarding-for-the-coding-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are going to go over a set of coding and whiteboard problems that would be asked during a coding interview. I&amp;rsquo;m drawing these problems from &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/&#34;&gt;LeetCode&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Cracking-Coding-Interview-Programming-Questions/dp/0984782850/ref=pd_lpo_sbs_14_t_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=2E72V7DJM4CV4DNTBTKD&#34;&gt;Cracking the Coding Interview&lt;/a&gt;. They are a sample of the medium and hard problems that require a bit of thinking and and familiarity with some fundamental data structures in computer science.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coding Interview: What to Expect</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/the-coding-interview-what-to-expect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/the-coding-interview-what-to-expect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being great at coding interviews doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily make you a great developer and being a great developer doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily make you great at interviews. However, you need to pass the interview to get the job. Most tech companies, public or startups, have started drawing from the same pool of interview material, adopted the same set of coding challenges and problems for candidates to solve. Coding interviews can be challenging and stressful, but with enough practice, research, and preparation, it can be very manageable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Career Transition Guide For Overachievers</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/a-career-transition-guide-for-overachievers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/a-career-transition-guide-for-overachievers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing strikes more anxiety and self-doubt than the dreaded job interview. The thought of participating in an activity designed for the sole purpose of evaluating your worth and the potential for rejection is enough to discourage many people from applying to jobs for which they lack all of the qualifications requested by the job posting. While qualification is important to accomplish the advertised job, it is not everything an employer looks for in a person they want to hire to be a part of the team, to grow with the company and help the company grow. The goal of this article is to provide a guide based on my personal experience for how to prepare for getting offers from jobs for which you don&amp;rsquo;t have all the qualifications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Employee Loyalty Important?</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/is-employee-loyalty-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/is-employee-loyalty-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;High-value employees are a major assets for a strong company. Losing a high contributing team member could leave a void and impact the team&amp;rsquo;s morale and workflow. Investors are also concerned by high turnover rates, especially amongst the senior executives. Groupon had trouble retaining their senior executives, which contributed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zeNQE3VBRnQ&#34;&gt;an 85% drop in their value&lt;/a&gt; a year after going public. It&amp;rsquo;s clear we want to &lt;strong&gt;retain&lt;/strong&gt; high-valued employees, but is &lt;strong&gt;employee loyalty&lt;/strong&gt; the way to achieve retention?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Hugo To Build A Personal Brand Website</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/using-hugo-to-build-a-personal-brand-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/using-hugo-to-build-a-personal-brand-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not always clear why we need need a personal website. But here&amp;rsquo;s the truth: we are a product (a brand) with unique skills to offer to prospective employees and customers. A website is an effective medium to let the world know who we are, what we are capable of, and what our values are. Building a personal website has never been easier these days with tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Formal Education May Close Doors To Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-formal-education-may-close-doors-to-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-formal-education-may-close-doors-to-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The average completion rate of Online Open Course (MOOC) certification programs is abysmally low. &lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2889436&#34;&gt;A report published in 2016 by researchers at Harvard and MIT&lt;/a&gt; based on 4 years of data indicated an average certification completion rate of just 5.5%. This does not discredit MOOCs to be a good source of quality education content for those looking for good information to improve their understanding for a particular subject; however, the depressing statistics underlines a deeper concern with the ineffectiveness of using a college curriculum to steer people&amp;rsquo;s professional development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
