<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Xiaoyun Yang</title>
    <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Xiaoyun Yang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying Algorithmic Thinking To Solve A Problem In JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/applying-algorithmic-thinking-to-solve-a-problem-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/applying-algorithmic-thinking-to-solve-a-problem-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a deep dive of a coding challenge that my friend was asked to solve during an interview. I like this problem a lot because the solution requires both algorithmic thinking and familiarity with some fundamental frameworks and techniques in computer science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Military To Tech Entrepreneur:  How I made the Leap</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/from-military-to-tech-entrepreneur--how-i-made-the-leap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/from-military-to-tech-entrepreneur--how-i-made-the-leap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I commissioned to serve in the US Navy when I received my university degrees. The service commitment is 5 years. I signed the contract when I was a sophomore in college. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that I wanted to be a tech entrepreneur or wanted to work in the high tech industry when I was in college. It was not until a year after I commissioned that I realized that I prefer a job in innovation and allows me to be creative and indulge in hands-on problem solving. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last 5 years exploring my interests and working on closing skills gaps that would preclude me from a smooth transition to a job I would enjoy doing. I did this while still serving in the military.  Here&amp;rsquo;s my journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use A Stress Journal To Turn Stress into An Action Plan</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/use-a-stress-journal-to-turn-stress-into-an-action-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/use-a-stress-journal-to-turn-stress-into-an-action-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kyle, a friend of mine, introduced me to his method for turning stress into an action plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Interview Study Guide For Overachievers</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/an-interview-study-guide-for-overachievers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/an-interview-study-guide-for-overachievers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing strikes more anxiety and self-doubt than the dreaded job interview. The thought of participating in an activity designed for the sole purpose of evaluating your worth and the potential for rejection is enough to discourage many people from applying to jobs for which they lack all of the qualifications requested by the job posting. While qualification is important to accomplish the advertised job, it is not everything an employer looks for in a person they want to hire to be a part of the team, to grow with the company and help the company grow. The goal of this article is to provide a guide based on my personal experience for how to prepare for getting offers from jobs for which you don&amp;rsquo;t have all the qualifications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Solving Using JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/problem-solving-using-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/problem-solving-using-javascript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is one of the most popular and versatile languages today, but when Brandon Eich first created JavaScript in 1995, it was not recognized as a general purpose programming language. JavaScript only ran in the browser and was primarily used to enhance the user interfaces of website (e.g., animation, effects upon hover), thus tightly coupled with the Data Object Model (DOM). In recent years, JavaScript has gotten a lot more useful as a general purpose language as it can be run independently from the DOM and browser. Additionally, JavaScript has also has gotten very sophisticated with the introduction of ES6 and ES7. With that, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at how JavaScript can be used to solve fundamental problems in computer science. Specifically, let&amp;rsquo;s look at how to write algorithms and leverage data structures to help us solve problems using JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything You Need To Know About Git</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/everything-you-need-to-know-about-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/everything-you-need-to-know-about-git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a cheatsheet of all the git commands that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever used in my career as a programmer and contributor of open source projects. I&amp;rsquo;m not a git power user (I use about three commands on a daily basis). From time to time, I still use this cheatsheet to for a quick lookup of a special command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Employee Loyalty Important?</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/is-employee-loyalty-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/is-employee-loyalty-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;High-value employees are a major assets for a strong company. Losing a high contributing team member could leave a void and impact the team&amp;rsquo;s morale and workflow. Investors are also concerned by high turnover rates, especially amongst the senior executives. Groupon had trouble retaining their senior executives, which contributed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zeNQE3VBRnQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an 85% drop in their value&lt;/a&gt; a year after going public. It&amp;rsquo;s clear we want to &lt;strong&gt;retain&lt;/strong&gt; high-valued employees, but is &lt;strong&gt;employee loyalty&lt;/strong&gt; the way to achieve retention?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Pay to Work At a Co-working Space</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/why-i-pay-to-work-at-a-co-working-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/why-i-pay-to-work-at-a-co-working-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you asked me to give you three facts about myself, I would tell you (1) I&amp;rsquo;m a evening and weekend entrepreneur, (2) when I start working on something I enjoy, I can&amp;rsquo;t put it down, and (3) I love coffee. This a formula for disaster because I have a full time job that I have to show up to by 9AM and I&amp;rsquo;m a normal human person who needs at least 6 hours of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Get Productive With JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/lets-get-productive-with-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/lets-get-productive-with-javascript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is one of the most popular and versatile languages today. You can build anything in JavaScript: from full stack web apps, to cross platform mobile apps, to cross platform desktop apps. Here are some useful algorithms and syntax in JavaScript to help you be productive in JavaScript right away. No set up necessary. Just  open up your browser&amp;rsquo;s console (hit &lt;code&gt;Cmd&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;code&gt;Shift&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;code&gt;C&lt;/code&gt; if you are using Chrome and Mac) and start typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Formal Education Closes Doors To Opportunities</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-formal-education-closes-doors-to-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-formal-education-closes-doors-to-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The average completion rate of Online Open Course (MOOC) certification programs is abysmally low. &lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2889436&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A report published in 2016 by researchers at Harvard and MIT&lt;/a&gt; based on 4 years of data indicated an average certification completion rate of just 5.5%. This does not discredit MOOCs to be a good source of quality education content for those looking for good information to improve their understanding for a particular subject; however, the depressing statistics underlines a deeper concern with the ineffectiveness of using a college curriculum to steer people&amp;rsquo;s professional development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Functional Programming Promotes Developer Productivity</title>
      <link>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-functional-programming-promotes-developer-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>http://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-functional-programming-promotes-developer-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Functional Programming is more than just a buzzword these days. It&amp;rsquo;s super useful and makes you rethink everything you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>