<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Xiaoyun Yang</title>
    <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Xiaoyun Yang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>When To Use Immutable Data Structures</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/when-to-use-immutable-data-structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/when-to-use-immutable-data-structures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Suppose you are asked this question during a technical interview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do you use immutable (functional) data structures and when do you use mutable data structure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cribsheet for JavaScript Coding Interview</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/cribsheet-for-javascript-coding-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/cribsheet-for-javascript-coding-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The coding interviews / coding challenges are designed to assess how productive someone can be with the language. In contrast to the algorithm whiteboarding interview, which assesses how the candidate go about solving a problem, or the architecture design interview, which assesses how the candidate&amp;rsquo;s experience in system engineering and product design, the coding interview is is utilized by the company interviewing you to answer one question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you be productive with JavaScript?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Structure with JavaScript Object: Linked List</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/data-structure-with-javascript-object-linked-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/data-structure-with-javascript-object-linked-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Linked list is like an array but more flexible. Elements in an array are stored contiguously in memory while linked lists are stored as nodes with two fields: current value and a pointer to the next thing in the list. We are going to implement linked list in JavaScript and go over some algorithms with the linked list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algos to Practice Whiteboarding for The Coding Interview</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/algos-to-practice-whiteboarding-for-the-coding-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/algos-to-practice-whiteboarding-for-the-coding-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are going to go over a set of coding and whiteboard problems that would be asked during a coding interview. I&amp;rsquo;m drawing these problems from &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LeetCode&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Cracking-Coding-Interview-Programming-Questions/dp/0984782850/ref=pd_lpo_sbs_14_t_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=2E72V7DJM4CV4DNTBTKD&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cracking the Coding Interview&lt;/a&gt;. They are a sample of the medium and hard problems that require a bit of thinking and and familiarity with some fundamental data structures in computer science.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coding Interview: What to Expect</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/the-coding-interview-what-to-expect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/the-coding-interview-what-to-expect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being great at coding interviews doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily make you a great developer and being a great developer doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily make you great at interviews. However, you need to pass the interview to get the job. Most tech companies, public or startups, have started drawing from the same pool of interview material, adopted the same set of coding challenges and problems for candidates to solve. Coding interviews can be challenging and stressful, but with enough practice, research, and preparation, it can be very manageable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles To Code By: How To Solve Problems With Code</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/principles-to-code-by-how-to-solve-problems-with-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/principles-to-code-by-how-to-solve-problems-with-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What I love most about programming is the problem solving. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe anyone is born with problem solving skills. It&amp;rsquo;s a muscle that is built and sustained by repeated exercise. Like any exercise, there&amp;rsquo;s a set of guidelines to help you be more effective at developing your problem solving muscles. I will introduce 5 of the most important software design principles that have guided my problem solving process and show you how to apply these principles to solve a real problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithms for Web Developers</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/algorithms-for-web-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/algorithms-for-web-developers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is one of the most popular and versatile languages today, but when Brandon Eich first created JavaScript in 1995, it was not recognized as a general purpose programming language. JavaScript only ran in the browser and was primarily used to enhance the user interfaces of website (e.g., animation, effects upon hover), thus tightly coupled with the Data Object Model (DOM). In recent years, JavaScript has gotten a lot more useful as a general purpose language as it can be run independently from the DOM and browser. Additionally, JavaScript has also has gotten very sophisticated with the introduction of ES6 and ES7. With that, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at how JavaScript can be used to solve fundamental problems in computer science. Specifically, let&amp;rsquo;s look at how to write algorithms and leverage data structures to help us solve problems using JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Get Productive With JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/lets-get-productive-with-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/lets-get-productive-with-javascript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is one of the most popular and versatile languages today. You can build anything in JavaScript: from full stack web apps, to cross platform mobile apps, to cross platform desktop apps. Here are some useful algorithms and syntax in JavaScript to help you be productive in JavaScript right away. No set up necessary. Just  open up your browser&amp;rsquo;s console (hit &lt;code&gt;Cmd&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;code&gt;Shift&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;code&gt;C&lt;/code&gt; if you are using Chrome and Mac) and start typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>