<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on Xiaoyun Yang</title>
    <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on Xiaoyun Yang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Open Sourced An ESLint Plugin for OkCupid</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-i-open-sourced-an-eslint-plugin-for-okcupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/how-i-open-sourced-an-eslint-plugin-for-okcupid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We developers often find ourselves faced with a problem that seems general enough and common enough that someone else could have already developed a solution for it. But what if an existing solution does not exist?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently open sourced an &lt;a href=&#34;https://eslint.org/docs/about/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ESLint&lt;/a&gt; plugin for OkCupid called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OkCupid/eslint-plugin-i18n-lingui&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;eslint-plugin-i18n-lingui&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The plugin is an extension for ESLint&amp;rsquo;s core static code analysis rules that enforces &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.smartling.com/resources/101/localization-101/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;localization&lt;/a&gt; best practices by catching and fixing errors during development. The best practice rules were inspired by the learning pains from our efforts to localize our website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will discuss why we developed our own ESLint plugin, why we open sourced it, and the steps I took to open source a ESLint plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this post will not discuss the localization best practices that &lt;code&gt;eslint-plugin-i18n-lingui&lt;/code&gt; enforces or how to create an ESLint plugin, keep an eye out for future posts written specifically about these!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thirsty Plant: Automated Plant Waterer</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/thirsty-plant-automated-plant-waterer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/thirsty-plant-automated-plant-waterer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xiaoyunyang&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Xiaoyun Yang&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/clydeshaffer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Clyde Shaffer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love indoor plants but I&amp;rsquo;m bad a keeping them alive. I once had a cactus that died from thirst. I purchased a few Aqua Bulbs, which has been great help in keeping the big plant watered enough for me to get around to taking care of it. However, I can&amp;rsquo;t use the Aqua Bulb on my smaller plant. Also, Aqua Bulbs break easily and refilling it with water is always a hassle. This motivated me to build an automated plant waterer. Let&amp;rsquo;s call it ThirstyPlant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Page Application For Work</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/single-page-application-for-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/single-page-application-for-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I work at my federal job on a close intranet network, we often had to access information from different databases and filesystems through custom or share point websites which did not have the best user interface. It was a pain point for me and many of my colleagues. I decided to make a set of single page applications (SPAs) with nicer UX for querying the databases and file systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building A React Native Travel App</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/building-a-react-native-travel-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/building-a-react-native-travel-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was planning my trip to Japan with some friends, I thought why not to use this opportunity to make a ReactNative mobile app to help you plan and execute your travel itinerary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Isomorphic Webapp</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/building-an-isomorphic-webapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/building-an-isomorphic-webapp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always lived by the &amp;ldquo;Separation of Concern&amp;rdquo; principle when it comes to software design.  Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve came to love a new design pattern for web apps called the isomorphic web app that sacrifices some of the simplicity of a SPA with a backend API for a significant boost in performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining a Repository Of Learning For Scala</title>
      <link>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/maintaining-a-repository-of-learning-for-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>xiaoyun@looseleafapp.com (Xiaoyun Yang)</author>
      <guid>https://xiaoyunyang.github.io/post/maintaining-a-repository-of-learning-for-scala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I maintain a knowledge repo on Github called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xiaoyunyang/coursera-scala-specialization&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;coursera-scala-specialization&lt;/a&gt;. One reason I chose to learn Scala is that Scala is a good language to learn functional programming and Scala offers full the functional programming support, but it also lets you do imperative programming and object oriented programming, with seamless interoperability with Java. Functional programming is a good paradigm that lets you make programs that are concise and modular. This is important for developer productivity which I care most about at this time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>